Guide to the Edgar Hockley Collection
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Designs by Production, Series II; Hockley, Edgar, 1860-1938
  - Faust: drawings of a female costume, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 2, Folder 8a)
    Includes color and detail notes for the costume. A smaller drawing depicts the detail on the cloak.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832. Faust
  - Faust: drawing of two males, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: pen and ink over graphite with gray wash and touches of gouache; 20 x 16 cm (Box 2, Folder 8b)
    Pen and ink drawings; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832. Faust; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Faust: drawing of three figures reaching upward in a fiery landscape, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor and gouache; 15.5 x 10.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 8c)
    Set design drawings; Watercolors; Costume design drawings; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832. Faust; Gouaches
  - Faust: drawing of Faust and Mephistopheles, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor and gouache; 9.5 x 15 cm (Box 2, Folder 8(d))
    Mephistopheles places his hand on Faust's shoulder. In the background, a skull rests atop a piece of furniture.
    Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832. Faust; Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Gouaches; Watercolors
  - Faust: drawing of Mephistopheles and another figure suspended in a dark void, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: gouache over graphite; 17.5 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 8e)
    Includes numerous dark figures swirling in the void below.
    Costume design drawings; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832. Faust; Set design drawings; Gouaches; Graphite drawings
  - Henry IV: drawing of a male with left hand extended, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hair, cloak, tunic, boots, satchel, hose, and a dagger.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1
  - Henry IV: drawing of Falstaff, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9b)
    Includes notes on the color of the costume and the styling of Falstaff's hair.
  - Henry IV: drawing of Lieutenant Bardolph, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9c)
    Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1; Costume design drawings
  - Henry IV: drawing of Poins' tunic and Falstaff with males, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9(d))
    Includes detail and color notes for Poins' tunic, as well as a drawing of Falstaff speaking to two males and another, smaller drawing of Falstaff.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1; Set design drawings
  - Henry IV: drawing of Poins with left view, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9e)
    Includes detail and color notes for Poins' collar, belt, gauntlets, hat, and boots.
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1; Graphite drawings
  - Henry IV: drawing of Poins (?), circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9f)
    Includes detail and color notes for Poins' (?) hat, collar, cloak, sleeves, sword, and boots.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Henry IV: drawing of Falstaff in profile, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9g)
    Falstaff, holding a mug, stands in front of a chair.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1; Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Henry IV: drawing of Bardolph with hat removed, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9h)
    Includes costume, hair, and makeup notes.
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1; Graphite drawings; Theatrical makeup
  - Henry IV: drawing of a room with fireplace, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 2, Folder 9.1a)
    Includes detail of a fireplace, wall paneling, and a banister, as well as silhouettes of numerous figures.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1
  - Henry IV: drawing of Edmund Mortimer, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9.1b)
    Includes detail and color notes on Mortimer's hair, tunic, belt, and boots.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1
  - Henry IV: drawings of Falstaff and other figures, circa 1886-1897; 7 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink and graphite; 11 x 7 cm (Box 2, Folder 9.1c)
    Drawings portray Falstaff and other figures in various poses, including three with swords aloft.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings
  - Henry IV: drawings of Falstaff and the exterior of a tavern, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 9.1d)
    Drawings portray the profile of Falstaff as well as a detailed rendering of the exterior of a tavern, outside of which Falstaff reclines on a bench. The tavern drawing includes notes on the set's materials and color.
  - Henry IV: drawing of a building exterior, with Falstaff and others, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 9.1e)
    Drawing depicts a gate, the exterior of a building, and 11 figures, including Falstaff and a woman referred to as "Hooker 2."
  - Henry IV: drawings of a male and a female, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 9.1(f))
    Includes costume detail and color notes for a male and female, the latter of which is referred to as "Hooker no 2."
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Henry IV: drawing of a wooded battle scene, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 9.1g)
    Seven figures, including Falstaff, pose as though in battle.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Set design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1
  - Henry VIII: drawing of a male from rear, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes color and detail notes on the tunic, stockings, cape, and cap.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry VIII; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a Roman male with soldiers in the background, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor and graphite; 12 x 7 cm (Box 2, Folder 11a)
    Watercolors; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a female embracing a male, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: pen and ink with watercolor and gouache; 13.5 x 8 cm (Box 2, Folder 11b)
    The drawing has "G. Harrison Esq" written on the verso.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Pen and ink drawings; Graphite drawings; Watercolors; Set design drawings; Gouaches; Costume design drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a male with arms crossed, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: pen and ink with watercolor and gouache; 13.5 x 8 cm (Box 2, Folder 11c)
    In the background, three faint figures watch from under an archway.
    Pen and ink drawings; Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Gouaches; Watercolors; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a female atop steps, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor and gouache over graphite; 9 x 12 cm (Box 2, Folder 11d)
    A female atop some steps speaks to a male while three other males look on. "G. Harrison Esq" is written on the verso.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Watercolors; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Gouaches
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a verdant courtyard with statues, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.1a)
    Includes detail and color notes for trees, statues, flowers, etc.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Set design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a courtyard with numerous figures, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 7 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.1b)
    Includes 13 figures in a courtyard with a wall, trees, decorations on buildings, and steps.
    Watercolors; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Set design drawings; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of the view from inside a building looking out, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.1c)
    Depicts two figures, including one soldier, in a building. The watercolor is faded.
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of Cassius and another male in a room, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.1d)
    Depicts Cassius and one other male in a room. Includes detail and color notes on the room decor and costumes.
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Set design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a portico overlooking a garden, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.1e)
    Includes color and detail notes for a wall, a temple, flora, several tiger skins, etc. The text on the verso notes: "Fence same color as columns."
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of an interior with three females, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 7 x 14 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.1(f))
    Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Costume design drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawings of a costume for a female, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.1g)
    Includes detail and color notes for the character's costume, hair, and skin.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of soldiers holding a male character aloft in celebration, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 12 x 19 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.1h)
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a courtyard with a statue of Caesar, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.1i)
    Drawing (3.5 x 6.5) is affixed to the larger sheet. Includes detail and color notes for the house, trees, statue, fountain, etc.
    Graphite drawings; Watercolors; Set design drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawings of a female from various scenes, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 12 x 19 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2a)
    Includes detail and color notes for 4 costume variations.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of Caesar on a chariot, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 12 x 19 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2b)
    Various figures watch as Caesar drives a chariot through a wooded area. Marks on the paper show that the sheet was once folded in three places.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Set design drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of Caesar on the ground surrounded by figures, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 17.5 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2c)
    Various figures gather around the fallen Caesar, with a backdrop of Roman architecture.
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a Roman arch, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2d)
    Includes detail and color notes for the arch, columns, ground, and window coverings.
    Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Set design drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawings of a toga as worn by a female, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings: graphite; 19.5 x 12 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2e)
    Includes detailed, alphabetically-organized instructions on how to don the costume. The verso finishes the instructions with: "Is now made tight to head."
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of numerous figures in togas, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 12 x 19 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2(f))
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a courtyard and a Griffin, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 19 x 12 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2g)
    Includes detail and color notes for the foliage, columns, sky, and the Griffin.
    Set design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a male in a toga holding a staff, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 10 x 6 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2h)
  - Julius Caesar: drawings of figures in various poses, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 10 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2i)
    Includes drawings of two figures embracing, a figure sitting on a curved bench, a male walking with a staff, three figures in togas, and another figure kneeling.
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Julius Caesar; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings
  - Julius Caesar: drawing of a courtyard, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 19 cm (Box 2, Folder 11.2j)
    Includes color notes for walls, roof tiles, foliage, the ground, and the ornaments on a building.
  - King John: drawing of Austria, Philip Augustus, and King John, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 12a)
    Depicts a scene in front of a castle gate, and includes detail and color notes for the characters' costumes.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King John; Set design drawings; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - King John: drawings of Queen Elinor and Chatillon, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 12b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the characters' costumes, as well as a background interior set with a staircase.
  - King John: drawing of a battle outside a castle, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 12c)
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King John; Set design drawings
  - King John: drawings of female costume, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 12d)
    Includes color and detail notes for wreath, hair, dress, satchel band, bodice, etc.
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King John; Graphite drawings
  - King John: drawing of a building exterior and an arch, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 12 x 19 cm (Box 2, Folder 12e)
    Includes color and detail notes for building, awnings, stones, and arch.
    Set design drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King John
  - King John: drawings of male costume, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 12(f))
    Includes color and detail notes for tunic, cloak, dagger, slippers, etc.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King John; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Louis XI: drawing of Louis and Oliver, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor and gouache over graphite; 18 x 23 cm (Box 2, Folder 13a)
    The watercolor (9 x 7.5) is affixed to a larger sheet, which includes color and detail notes for the tunics, faces, fur, hose, etc.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Delavigne, Casimir, 1793-1843. Louis XI; Theatrical makeup; Watercolors; Gouaches
  - Louis XI: drawing of male in armor, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11.5 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 13b)
    Includes color and detail notes for the armor, mace, cape, etc.
    Delavigne, Casimir, 1793-1843. Louis XI; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Louis XI: drawings of Celia, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink; 20 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 13c)
    Includes color and detail notes for the headdress, medal, bodice, skirt, etc. Reverse of sheet includes the beginning outline of another drawing.
    Delavigne, Casimir, 1793-1843. Louis XI; Costume design drawings; Pen and ink drawings
  - Louis XI: drawing of a male and a female, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 13d)
    Includes detail and color notes for the helmet, tunic, hose, dress, cloak, etc.
    Delavigne, Casimir, 1793-1843. Louis XI; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Lyon's Mail: drawings of males, circa 1886-1897; 8 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 22.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 14a)
    Includes drawings of characters from Lyon's Mail, The Bells, and Louis XI. The verso also has two drawings from an unidentified play.
    Delavigne, Casimir, 1793-1843. Louis XI; Graphite drawings; Lewis, Leopold, d. 1890. The Bells; Reade, Charles, 1814-1884. Lyon's Mail; Costume design drawings
  - Macbeth: drawings of tapestry, figures on horses, and two figures, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 15a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the tapestry and the riders of the horses. A "Doorway on Owen Glendower Palace" is mentioned in one note, possibly linking the drawing to Henry IV.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Henry IV. Part 1; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Lear; Costume design drawings; Set design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Merchant of Venice: drawings of Portia and a bearded man, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink; 14 x 19 cm (Box 2, Folder 16a)
    The verso includes a very faint drawing of multiple figures.
    Pen and ink drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Merchant of Venice
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream: drawings of a female with arms outstretched, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink and graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 17a)
    Includes three views of same pose, as well as color and detail notes for the costume and hair.
    Costume design drawings; Pen and ink drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Midsummer night's dream
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream: drawing of a male in a horned costume, his arms around two women, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 12 x 14.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 17b)
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Midsummer night's dream
  - Richard III: drawing of Lady Anne, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 18a)
    Includes color and detail notes for the dress, cloak, turban, etc.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Richard III; Arthur, Julia, 1869-1950
  - Richard III: drawings of a chamber scene, a musician, a soldier, and a cardinal, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 2, Folder 18b)
    The chamber scene, depicting four characters, appears on one side of the sheet. The verso features the soldier, musician, cardinal, and a female character, and includes color and detail notes.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Richard III
  - Richard III: drawings of a hunchback, Biondello, and a bearded male, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 12 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 18c)
    Includes color and detail notes for the costumes. Multiple productions may be depicted in the drawing, as Biondello is a character in Taming of the Shrew.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Richard III; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Taming of the shrew
  - Romeo and Juliet: drawings of Juliet leaning on the balcony, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 19a)
    Includes color notes for the balcony.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Romeo and Juliet
  - Romeo and Juliet: drawings of Romeo's costume and two figures near a wall, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 10 x 14 cm (Box 2, Folder 19b)
    Includes color and detail notes for Romeo's costume. The sheet on which the drawings were made is cut into an L-shape.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Romeo and Juliet; Set design drawings; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Romeo and Juliet: drawings of Juliet and the balcony, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 19c)
    Includes color and detail notes for Juliet's hair and dress, as well as set design notes for the balcony. One note says: "see Becket curtain, throne scene."
    Set design drawings; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Romeo and Juliet
  - Romeo and Juliet: drawing of a garden and a balcony, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 19d)
    Reverse side of drawing features the beginnings of a drawing of a structure.
    Set design drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Romeo and Juliet
  - She Stoops to Conquer: drawing of Marlow and Hastings, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 20a)
    Includes color and detail notes on the waistcoats, overcoats, breeches, boots, etc.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Goldsmith, Oliver, 1730?-1774. She stoops to conquer
  - The Three Musketeers: drawing of a swordfight, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 8.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 21a)
    The reserve side of the sheet features the faint beginnings of another drawing.
    Set design drawings; Graphite drawings; Dumas, Alexandre, 1802-1870. Trois mousquetaires. English; Costume design drawings
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of a swordsman and Queen Anne, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 21b)
    Includes color and detail notes for the cloak, tunic, belt, knickers, and dress.
    Costume design drawings; Set design drawings; Dumas, Alexandre, 1802-1870. Trois mousquetaires. English; Pen and ink drawings
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of a swordsman in various poses and a female, circa 1886-1897; 6 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 17.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 21c)
    Includes color and detail notes for costumes.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Dumas, Alexandre, 1802-1870. Trois mousquetaires. English
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of the Queen, Musketeers, and others, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 21d)
    Includes color and detail notes for the dress, hat, hose, cloaks, etc.
    Dumas, Alexandre, 1802-1870. Trois mousquetaires. English; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of a male and a female, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 21e)
    Includes color and detail notes for the hat, hair, sword, jacket, stockings, slipper, cloak, and dress.
    Costume design drawings; Dumas, Alexandre, 1802-1870. Trois mousquetaires. English; Graphite drawings
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of a swordsman, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 24 x 18.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 21(f))
    Includes color and detail notes for the hat, breeches, boots, sword, tunic, hair, cloak, etc.
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of a male with a cloak and hat, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 21g)
    Includes color and detail notes for the hair, cloak, hat, boots, etc.
  - The Three Musketeers: drawings of a male with a hat on his knee, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 12 x 20 cm (Box 2, Folder 21.1a)